Aaron Mulholland

Academy Trainer at QA Consulting

aaron.mulholland@live.co.uk

Summary

I am a highly productive and motivated graduate with a good understanding of computing gained from my University degree and working with computers since a young age. I gained experience mentoring peers whilst at University which has enabled me to develop on my public speaking skills, having delivered presentations to a large number of students. This sparked a new-found interest in the tutelage of others which he has applied in his current role training graduates.

Throughout my work in retail I gained transferable skills from effective professional communication to teamwork and team management, having previously worked in a sports shop working with the public in a fast-paced environment. I further developed my communication skills and professionalism, specifically focusing on how to engage with a customer and how to deal with goods-trading issues that may arise at any time.

Through his experience with personal and educational projects, I have developed the ability to adapt to change quickly. This could be a project that may require changing at the last minute, or a progressive change. I am able to communicate effectively with colleagues, peers and clients, knowing how to engage with the person, understanding when to listen and when to speak.

During my time working as an Academy Trainer I have gained further skills in training others in a specific technology, after first going away and gathering knowledge & experience on the technology to create training material. I have also gained further skills in professional development having worked on CV creation and interview preparation with Academy Trainees.

Experience

Academy Trainer at QA Consulting

June 2014 - Present (2 years)

My role within the Academy is to provide high quality training in various in-demand technologies. With skills in CI & DevOps with Puppet, Chef, Testing, Sitecore, C# & .NET, AEM and Hybris, I cover a lot of the middleware technologies seen during the last four weeks of training.

QA Consulting is a leading provider of Consulting Services to world leading commercial and financial institutions, as well as some of the UK's largest Government departments.

We operate a unique customer enablement programme in which we recruit, train and supply our own specialist consultants in prominent Middleware, SaaS, Big Data and WCM technologies.

We partner with leading software vendors where in-market skill shortages are apparent, costs are high, and flight risk or typical integrator engagements often mean loss of IP for customers.

Partners include:

- Pega
- Cloudera
- Sitecore
- Puppet
- ServiceNow
- SmartBear
- Oracle

If you're interested in this opportunity and want to discuss more; drop an email with your CV to me directly at aaron.mulholland@qa.com

Casual Sales Assistant at SportsDirect

May 2012 - May 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Casual Sales Assistant working on average 20 - 30 hours a week at the local store whilst completing my degree at University.

Student Ambassador at Oldham College

June 2010 - June 2011 (1 year 1 month)

My main roles and responsibilities involved attending open days at various local schools, and large school leaver events.

Overall my role was to support and provide legitimate information regarding the college, and ensure school leavers had enough information to make an informed decision about there further education.

Library Assistant at Counthill School

September 2005 - May 2009 (3 years 9 months)

I began by looking after the library, stacking shelves - keeping to the dewy decimal system, organising the lunch-time computer booking system and loaning out books to pupils.

After four years, I became the Head of the LRC in my fifth year at the school (Year 11) and along side my studies ensured the library stayed open at all times with a smooth running operation.

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Certifications

ISTQB-ISEB Certified Tester Foundation Level

BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT November 2014

Volunteer Experience

Waiter at Salt Cellar Cafe

February 2009 - March 2010

It was an experience which during my young age, I was able to assist with the running of a charitable church café that helped raise money for the homeless and poor.

Not only did my work assist others, but it taught me some great values including the benefit of donating just a day a week to better someone else's life.

Media Organiser at Cancer Research UK

August 2009 - December 2009

Skills & Expertise

Public Speaking

Time Management

Software Development

Team Leadership

Peer Tutoring

Training

Peer Mentoring

PowerPoint

Java

Git

Microsoft Office

Windows

Docker

Continuous Integration

HTML

Ubuntu

Functional Testing

Leadership

Non-functional Testing

Black Box Testing

White Box Testing

Project Management

Data Analysis

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Word

C#

English

AEM

Manual Testing

Continuous Delivery

Red Hat Linux

Debian

RedHat

DevOps

SSH

Puppet

Vagrant

Jenkins

Maven

JIRA

Hybris

Spring IoC

Spring AOP

Spring MVC

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Education

Edge Hill University

Bachelor of Science (BS) (Hons), Computing (Application Development), 2011 - 2014

Grade: First Class With Honours

Oldham College

BTEC National Diploma, National Diploma in Performing Arts: Acting, 2009 - 2011

Grade: Triple Grade Distinction

Activities and Societies: Acting, Theatre productions, theatre trips, team building skills, presentational skills.

Interests

Training and Mentoring, Counselling, Program Development, Musical activities, travelling.

Aaron Mulholland

Academy Trainer at QA Consulting

aaron.mulholland@live.co.uk



2 people have recommended Aaron

"Aaron is an excellent trainer, with a welth of knowledge and is aways enthusiastic and willing to help."

— Morgan Thomas Atkins, Consultant, NETbuilder, reported to Aaron at QA Consulting

"Aaron is an extremely enthusiastic programmer, who tenaciously chases a problem until a solution is found. He is capable of tapping into a wealth of information in an extremely efficient manner, in order to get the job done."

— Chris Cooney, was with another company when working with Aaron at Oldham College

Contact Aaron on LinkedIn